Andrew Fyfe

Tel: 07549 925212 **Email:** andfyfe@fastmail.fm

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/anfyfe

Github: enumera

Personal website: andrewfyfe.mansci.co.uk

Profile

I recently graduated from the General Assembly Web Development Immersive course. I really enjoyed the course and not only that I enjoyed meeting the people there and immersing myself in the tech culture.

Prior to this course I was an ISEB qualified, freelance business process and systems analyst and test manager, interchangeably. I managed teams in tight timescales and pressured projects to deliver whatever the business requirement was.

Projects I worked on usually had large elements of actuarial, mathematical and data management issues and the main skill I took from all my jobs was being able to communicate and articulate requirements, processes or issues to technical business experts, business processors, programme managers, testers and my team; each one requiring a different context and coming from varying backgrounds. This required me to have knowledge of the high level architecture, the processes, business technical and IT requirements to the small details.

I would like a role that merges my current and new skills; talking to the business, the makers and doers and be one of the team that build awesome applications to enhance the life and work of people who use them. There is nothing more satisfying that hearing someone say: 'I'd use that' after checking out the app that you and a team built.

Experience

Web Developer immersive course at General Assembly(GA) - 2014 My projects were:

- *GA class scheduler*: This app managed the resources of GA, current students and applications from new students to support the growing GA business. The app was built using **Ruby on Rails** with **postgres, CSS3 and HTML5** and managed through **GitHUB**.
- WiFind: This was a group project which I really enjoyed; I was the group leader. This
 app allows users to find, manage and check out local amenities that have free wifi. The
 project was built with Ruby on Rails with postgres, google maps, google OAuth,
 javascript, jquery, CSS3 and HTML5 and managed with GitHUB.
- List more with resindex: This was my final project, a group task delegation app with a bespoke index that I devised myself to manage and priortise tasks through time. The app was built with AngularJS, Ruby on Rails with prostgres, javascript, jquery and managed through GitHUB. Google and twitter OAuth were employed with feed of posts from twitter for users that want it.

IFDS, Test Manager - Oct 2013 - June 2014

Consulted to the wider programme on testing calculations in a large data migration and infrastructure project, I also managed a team of eight testers to implement that test strategy. I had exposure to various technologies; .NET, oracle databases, XML, Quality Center for test management, system infrastructure development and testing.

Prudential Group, Actuarial business systems analyst - June 2011-Sept 2013

I was part of the business team that managed the specification and delivery of a complex bespoke set of systems for the management of operational and financial risk for Prudential Group to meet Solvency II standards; in the UK, USA and Pacific-Asia region.

I facilitated workshops, engineered and specified requirements for an in-house IT team as well as two other third-party software houses. I supported all IT teams and testers throughout the testing phase and business users across all regions on delivery of the system as well as comminucating the group context and ethos behind the processes and systems we put in place for Solvency II. I was a member of the programme management team for the duration of my time at Prudential, managing issues in production as well as development. This project used various technologies; Java, Algo system bespoke language Riskscript, Risk++, MATLAB and XML. Configuration was managed through MKS.

Pearl Assurance, Business system analyst, Jan 2011 - Jun 2011

Created the business systems architecture for reporting for Solvency II and began the work to implement the strategy to deliver it. I left to move to London and work for Prudential.

Standard Life, Data management test manager.

Produced a test strategy to test the management of data through new bespoke systems that were to be built to support Solvency II requirements. Architecture and technologies were not established at this point in the programme.

Pearl Assurance, Actuarial systems analyst, Jan 2010 - Jun 2010

Consulted on the initial start of the project to build a bespoke enterprise system to manage financial risk within the company.

Admin Re. (subsidiary of Swiss Re), Calculations Test Manager, Oct 2007- Oct 2009

Test manager leading a team of ten testers on all calculations for eight consecutive data migrations to the same in-house policy administration system built using Cobol and .NET.

Education

- General Assembly Web Developer Immersive
- June 2014 (12 weeks)
- Open University Understand systems: making sense of complexity
- 2009
- ISEB Diploma in business systems analysis/ Six Sigma Green Belt
- 2006
- University of Stirling Bsc(Hons) in Management science and mathematics
- 2001 2005

Interests

I love hillwalking in the UK and abroad, I regularly go on activity/tourist holidays, for example, cycling through Jordan or cross-country skiing in Norway. I am an active member of the LRUG community and have also recently experienced hackathons and intend to attend many more.

I am a firm believer that education and adventure are the best investment in yourself so I am always up to one or the other!